<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: programming | Koolistov]]></title>
  <link href="http://koolistov.net/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://koolistov.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-19T11:00:46+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://koolistov.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Johan Kool]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Developer Tool Tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://koolistov.net/blog/2012/01/10/two-developer-tool-tips/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T20:54:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://koolistov.net/blog/2012/01/10/two-developer-tool-tips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two quick tips for fixing some troubles with developer tools. I ran into both today, though they are likely unrelated. I couldn't find much about it online, so here goes.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>FileMerge won't open for third party app</h2>

<p>When trying to view differences using GitBox, nothing would happen. This symptom started after I had installed a beta version of Xcode. Once I realized that GitBox opens FileMerge via the command line utlity <code>opendiff</code> the fix was easy: selecting the proper Xcode installation.</p>

<p>This is done as such:</p>

<pre><code>xcode-select -switch /path/to/developer-folder
</code></pre>

<h2>Symbolicating crash logs failed</h2>

<p>When trying to symbolicate some crash logs I got this error:</p>

<pre><code>Error: Can't run /usr/share/xcode-select/xcrun (no such file).
</code></pre>

<p>This was somewhat puzzling, because also on my other Mac, where symbolicating crash logs did work, there was no such file.</p>

<p>The command line utility <code>xcrun</code> is by the way what is used by a number of scripts to find out which Developer folder to use.</p>

<p>Luckily the fix turned out to be quite straightforward: reinstall <code>xcrun</code>. Simply reinstalling Xcode does the trick, or you can take the shortcut I took, and go into the Install Xcode bundle to find <code>xcrun.pkg</code> in <code>/Contents/Resources/Packages/</code>.</p>

<p>Once that installer package was installed, <code>xcrun</code> ran happily again.</p>

<p>To symbolicate crash logs you run this command:</p>

<pre><code>/Developer/Platforms/iPhoneOS.platform/Developer/Library/PrivateFrameworks/DTDeviceKit.framework/Versions/A/Resources/symbolicatecrash /path/to/crash-log
</code></pre>

<p>(Yes, you probably should use some way to shorten that.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
