<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ios5 | Koolistov]]></title>
  <link href="http://koolistov.net/blog/categories/ios5/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://koolistov.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-26T21:45:11+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://koolistov.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Johan Kool]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Antiquated Icons and Junk Drawers]]></title>
    <link href="http://koolistov.net/blog/2011/09/24/antiquated-icons-and-junk-drawers/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-24T21:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://koolistov.net/blog/2011/09/24/antiquated-icons-and-junk-drawers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the perks of having a newborn in the house, besides dirty diapers and frequent feedings, is that you only get up-to-date on some news later than normal. During the last weeks I had been hearing about Windows 8 and the new Metro style apps Microsoft introduced, but it wasn't until this morning that I found some time to look at one of the introduction videos.</p>

<p>Actually, I have to congratulate Microsoft on this one. Like mine (yes, not a subjective opinion, but who cares) theirs is a pretty baby too! A fresh and unique approach is something we don't often see coming out of Redmond. The tiles, the side-by-side mode, sharing between apps are all great features to have. Also smaller things like being able to swipe between pages whilst dragging is a fun new gesture.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>My Desktop is Not a Phone</h3>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Microsoft would have done better to introduce Metro for just touch devices.'>
But it wouldn't be Microsoft if there weren't a number of rather baffling decisions. I can see Metro style apps work beautifully on touch devices like phones and, in Microsofts parlance, slates. On desktop and laptop computers without touch these apps are woofully out of place. As a iOS developer I have some experience here, as I often debug apps running in the iOS Simulator. For debugging that works great, but I'd never want to use an app that way on my desktop all day long. Some gestures are nearly impossible, or even completely impossible. Think pinching, rotating, or anything involving more than one finger. Yet, Metro apps are expected to be able to be driven by mouse and keyboard too. If developers have to take that usage method into account, they are targeting the lowest common denominator. You don't want that.</p>

<p>When Apple announced that with Lion the new features and ideas learned from iOS would make it 'back to the Mac', they were actually quite conservative in what they brought along. The current desktop metaphor is still a strong one, and it works wonderfully well with a keyboard and mouse (or trackpad, or both). Apple didn't put a touchscreen in their desktops and laptops, nor do the let you run iOS apps on the Mac. For a good reason: it doesn't fit that usage type. Microsoft would have done better to introduce Metro for just touch devices. It would have been a great time also to drop the "Windows" name, which in a chromeless UI as Metro is now just a plain silly name. I think Microsoft also underestimates the negative association many people make when they hear the name "Windows".</p>

<p>Today's trend is towards touch. Microsoft correctly saw that. The desktop computer as we know it is here to stay though, that is, with keyboard and mouse. I see desktops and touch devices getting more and more acquainted with each other, but I doubt they'll ever become one and the same. Just as you don't connect a mouse to your touch device, bringing touch to your desktop computer won't do the trick either.
</span></p>

<h3>Apple, er... Window Push Notifications</h3>

<p>But back to Metro, because on touch devices it looks rather promising. I had a good chuckle when they started talking about push notifications. They call this service "Windows Push Notifications Service", abbreviated as "WNS", I guess abbreviating it as "WPNS" was to close to "APNS" as Apple's push notification service is known. These days having push notifications in your OS is definitely a must. It took Apple until iOS 5 before it finally introduced a notification center. I don't think I break any NDA rules if I say that I really love having this feature on my iPhone. Microsoft has decided otherwise: "That," they say, "is not a notification center, but a junk drawer. All those notifications pile up there, and you have to go clean them up or eventually your drawer will overflow with junk." I wonder how long it will take them to make a full 180 and eat their words on this.</p>

<h3>App Branding</h3>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Using an icon is now considered &#8220;antiquated&#8221; by Microsoft.'>
Using an icon is now considered "antiquated" by Microsoft. Funny language to hear from the masters of backward compatibility to the extreme. Although I like the general idea of the live tiles over icons, there is one major concern that I have here. It waters down for the user what is your app and what is the OS. This is further emphasized by the use of templates for the live tiles. The icon, before the most important branding an app had, is now a generic tile. Also within the apps Microsoft wants developers to use Microsofts templates and Microsofts typography and Microsofts layout. If the non-geek user already has trouble naming their web browser, in Metro they will have an even harder time identifying which app they are using if they even recognize it as such. I think that as Metro app developer it will be a big challenge to gain name recognition for your Metro app.
</span></p>

<h3>Competition Welcome</h3>

<p>Although there is a lot of new stuff, it is evident Microsoft took a good look at Apple's iOS. I don't doubt the reverse will happen too, and would welcome side-by-side apps in iOS 6. Also the sharing services are great additions and a good feature to have in a mobile OS. It is good that Apple is facing some more competition here now. Until now competition was not too impressive: Android is still playing catchup, WebOS is being kicked around by CEOs and Blackberry... not sure why I even mention them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
